<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts | Md Sayeef Alam</title>
    <link>/pw/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="/pw/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/pw/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Posts</title>
      <link>/pw/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to stall COVID’s march in rural India</title>
      <link>/pw/post/covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/pw/post/covid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The country-wide lockdown imposed by Prime Minister Narendra Modi from March 25, 2020, impaired the lives of many urban migrants who lost their jobs overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all modes of public transport being suspended, urban migrants had no choice but to walk on foot to their native places. P Sainath, veteran development journalist, called it a “gigantic movement in Indian history.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After many cities lurched under its calamitous impact, the novel coronavirus has unearthed a new hunting ground in rural areas. With several migrants returning to their native places, there has been a trend reversal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rural areas of many districts are now reporting an upsurge in the number of confirmed cases of novel coronavirus disease (COVID-19). The World Health Organization’s chief scientist, Soumya Swaminathan, has also expressed her concern, stating that rural India is the next coronavirus hotbed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Uttar Pradesh, West Bengal, Madhya Pradesh, Bihar, Assam, Odisha and Jharkhand, that are now witnessing a heavy spike in the number of cases, are the states that have received the highest influx of migrants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rural areas of Rajasthan and Karnataka have also started to record an escalation in the number of cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly 6.7 million migrants returned to 116 districts in six states from urban centres, according to preliminary data compiled by the Union Ministry of Skill Development and Entrepreneurship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of them, about 4.4 million or two-thirds returned to 53 districts. Bihar topped the six states, with 2.36 million migrants returning to 32 districts, followed by Uttar Pradesh, with 1.748 million returning to 31 districts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continue reading with the following link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/health/how-to-stall-covid-s-march-in-rural-india-72358&#34;&gt;https://www.downtoearth.org.in/blog/health/how-to-stall-covid-s-march-in-rural-india-72358&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
